Previously on
Space Brothers
むった
＜不運に縁がある兄･六太＞
Older brother Mutta is plagued by bad luck.
＜栄光の日生まれの
ひびと
弟･日々人は➡
Born under a lucky star, younger brother Hibito becomes the first Japanese moonwalker.
日本人 初の
ムーンウォーカーとなった＞
Older brother Mutta seeks to become an astronaut, and keep his promise to former teacher Sharon,
ぼうえんきょうけんせつ
＜月面望遠鏡建設を望む➡
おんし
恩師･シャロンとの
約束を果たすため➡
兄･六太は
宇宙飛行士を目指す＞
to build a telescope on the moon.
Mutta's made it through the first round, but he keeps running into trouble.
＜選抜試験を
かろ
辛うじて突破するが➡
訓練中もトラブルの連続
筆記試験では最低点＞
On the written test, he scores the lowest.
＜暴走教官が
飛行訓練の担当になる始末＞
And as a result, he's assigned to a wild flight instructor.
However, the older brother Mutta
＜だが困難に揉まれたおかげで➡
has yet to realize that he's rapidly learning the lessons he'll need to become an astronaut.
宇宙飛行士の大事な資質を➡
猛スピードで
身に付けていることに➡
兄･六太は まだ気づいていない＞
(デニール)カモ～ン｡
Come on!
なんば
＜デニール･ヤングとの日々が➡
I put my memories of Deneil Young in the notebook in my heart.
心のノートにメモられたのち…＞
I congratulate all my JAXA friends who have advanced from AsCans to astronauts.
むらさき
(紫)今回正式にアスキャンから➡
アストロノートへと認定される➡
ジャクサ
ＪＡＸＡの
新宇宙飛行士のみなさん｡
月から おめでとうを
言わせていただきます｡
All the way from the moon.
まかべ
にった
れいじ
[TV](紫)真壁ケンジ君 新田零次君➡
Makabe Kenji,
Nitta Reiji,
いとう
きたむら
えな
伊東せりかさん 北村絵名さん➡
Itou Serika,
Kitamura Ena,
南波六太君｡
Nanba Mutta...
As of today, we're allowed to call ourselves astronauts.
＜私達は今日から
｢宇宙飛行士｣と➡
名乗ることを許された＞
＜宇宙飛行士｢南波六太｣！＞
The astronaut Nanba Mutta...
失礼します｡
Excuse me!
You failed the written test and fell ill during training.
テストで落第点をとったり
訓練中に➡
コンディションを
大きく くずしたりと➡
正直 私には
君の この不安定さが他の者と➡
To be frank, your inconsistency makes you a weaker candidate in my eyes.
比べて どうしても
劣って見えてしまうがね｡
は はい｡
Y-Yes, sir...
だが なぜか君を推す者は➡
But lots of people are saying good things about you...
たくさんいるんだよね｡
In eighteen months, there's an open spot in the backup crew for a mission.
１年半後のミッションで➡
バックアップクルーの席に
まだ少し空きがある｡
バックアップクルーの重要性は
わかってるね｡
You understand how important the backup crew is, right?
プライムクルーの誰かが➡
If a member of the prime crew falls ill right before launch,
直前に体調ひとつ くずせば➡
代わりに宇宙へ行くべき人物だ｡
the backup crew member goes to space.
どうする？➡
Well?
It's your decision to make.
最終決定権は君にある｡
《マ マジかよ!?》
S-Seriously?
《俺がいきなり
バックアップクルー!?》
He's assigning me to the backup crew?
Th-That's crazy...
《す すごいぞ これは…》
《バックアップクルーとして➡
If I complete my training as a backup crew member,
すいこう
一通り訓練を遂行すれば➡
there's only one thing left...
その次はもう…》
《やった こんなに早く!!》
It's happening so fast.
⦅シャロン！⦆
Sharon!
⦅３年先か４年先か➡
It'll probably take three or four years before this will happen.
わかんね～けど俺の中じゃ➡
俺が誰より先に選ばれて➡
But I plan to be the first one chosen to go to the moon and build your telescope.
月で望遠鏡を建てる予定だよ⦆
《これなら
シャロンとの約束にも➡
I'll be able to keep my promise to Sharon
間に合う！》
with time to spare!
あのっ 月環境を想定した➡
Uh, would I be training for extra-vehicular activity on the moon?
せんがいかつどうくんれん
船外活動訓練とかも➡
やらせて もらえるんですか？
いや…➡
No.
無重力を想定した訓練なら
メニューにあるが➡
There will be some zero-gravity training,
今回 月は関係ないからな｡➡
but this mission doesn't involve the moon...
私が言っているのは
国際宇宙ステーション➡
This mission is for the International Space Station,
アイエスエス
ＩＳＳでのミッションだよ｡
the ISS.
《ＩＳＳ…!?》
The ISS?
It's just obvious that the more you put in your bag
The heavier it gets
The harder I work, the closer I get to my goal
But I'm just not getting there fast enough
I gaze at the night sky but it doesn't calm me down
Now that you've heard how loud my heart's beating
Let's take a trip outside
My starvation knows no bounds under this sea of stars
In this planetarium of dreams and reality
I'm currently updating the canvas of my dreams
With a glittering universe and a blue earth
My starvation knows no bounds under this sea of stars
In this planetarium of facades and honesty
I'm currently conversing with the canvas of my dreams
On this orbit of fate
With a fire in my belly
#70 Determination to Give Up
＜ＩＳＳが見られる
この１～２分間に➡
The minute or two I could see the ISS was my day's highlight many times.
私は何度も救われてきた＞
It's a worn-down piece of metal that's still working hard.
＜もうボロい船なのに
まだ現役で働いている＞
＜それぞれの覚悟を乗せたまま＞
On board, there's a lot of determination.
(せりか)⦅私は ＩＳＳに
とうじょう
搭乗したいんです⦆
I want to board the ISS.
＜１３年前の 2012年に宇宙ｽﾃｰｼｮﾝ
ＩＳＳは完成した＞
Thirteen years ago, in 2012, the ISS was completed.
However, NASA shifted their focus to Moonbase and Mars exploration.
ナサ
＜しかし ＮＡＳＡの関心は
月面基地と➡
たんさ
火星探査に移っていた＞
＜やがて 世間からも忘れられ
ろうきゅうか
老朽化も進んでいるＩＳＳは➡
Before long, the station was forgotten.
But so far, the ISS has survived old age by serving as a unique experimental environment.
とくしゅ
特殊医療研究の場所として
なんとか存続している状態だ＞
⦅せりかちゃん お父さんの
仕事を引き継ぐんだって｡➡
Serika wants to carry on her father's wish.
It requires developing a new medicine in zero gravity.
それで 可能性があるのは
無重力下での新薬の発見で➡
That can only be done
ゆいいつ
今 唯一 それができるのは…➡
ＩＳＳの｢きぼう｣
モジュールなんだって⦆
aboard the ISS's Kibo module.
《月じゃなくて
ＩＳＳでのミッション!?》
This mission is to the ISS, not the moon?
今 ＩＳＳには 君の先輩
ミヤタアツシがいる｡➡
Currently, a countryman of yours, Miyata Atsushi, is on board.
After becoming an astronaut, he waited five and a half years for his first flight.
彼は飛行士になってから ５年半
待って 念願の初フライトだ｡➡
Kisaki Sanae trained with him, and served as his backup.
そのミヤタと共に 同じ訓練を受け
にな
バックアップを担ったのが➡
キサキサナエだ｡彼女は
来年ＩＳＳに乗りこむ｡つまり…➡
Next year, she'll be boarding the ISS.
In other words,
I'm recommending you for her backup.
君に提案しているのは
キサキのバックアップだ｡
This is a rare opportunity.
なかなかないよ～｡新人がこんなに
ひか
テンポよく 控えに就ける話は｡
Rookies never get chosen as backups so quickly.
あれ…何？ピンと来ない？
Huh?
What's wrong? Overwhelmed?
す…すみません バトラー室長｡
I'm s-sorry, Chief Butler.
少し 考えさせてください｡
May I have some time to think it over?
Nitta and I will be preparing for lunar missions.
僕と新田君は 月ミッションの
方向に決まりそうだよ｡
Basically, we'll continue training while waiting for a spot to open.
とりあえず
今までの訓練も続けながら➡
にんめい
控えに任命されのを
待つって感じだね｡
Did you hear about Shane and Ben?
シェインとベンの話きいた？
Yeah.
あの２人はもう
月のバックアップクルー決定だろ｡
They've already been assigned to the backup crew for a lunar mission.
さっき ジェニファーが
ペラペラと言いまわってたよ｡
Jennifer was telling everyone she ran across.
ムッ君は？
What about you, Mu?
Right now, I'm still thinking it over.
俺は…今 悩んでるとこ｡
Huh?
もし ＩＳＳの方向に進んだら➡
If I choose to go to the ISS,
in three or four years, I have a high chance of making it into space.
最短で 今から３～４年後には
宇宙に行けるかもしれない｡
それは それで最高なんだけど…｡
That would be fantastic...
やっぱり俺は 月に行きたいんだ｡
But I want to go to the moon.
誘いにのったら 宇宙へは
近道だけど 月へは遠回りになる｡
If I accept this assignment,
it'll put me on the fast track to space, but I'll take longer to reach the moon.
True...
たしかに ＩＳＳと月とじゃ
訓練がまるで違うもんね｡
ISS training is completely different than for the moon.
If you start training for a lunar mission after returning from the ISS,
ＩＳＳの後 いちから
月の訓練をやるとなると…｡
また バックアップから始めて…｡
you'll have to land a backup spot first.
早くて８年後
まあ１０年後だな 月は｡
If I'm lucky, we're talking eight years.
I'd guess it'd be ten years before I reach the moon.
《結局のところ私は
悩んでなどいなかった》
I guess I didn't really need to think about it.
《私の一番の金ピカは
もう何年も…ずっと…》
My shining star
will always be
《こっちを見てる》
looking down on me.
月のことで頭いっぱいの僕より➡
Given that I'm completely focused on the moon, I believe there is a better candidate for the ISS.
優先すべき ふさわしい人が
いると思うんです｡
ほう 例えば？
Oh? Who would that be?
Itou Serika.
伊東せりかさんです｡
ゆず
席を譲れるなら ぜひとも彼女に！
If I had a choice, I would give her my spot.
なぜ イトウさんに？
もしかして 好きなの？
Why Itou?
Are you in love with her?
N-No, it's nothing like that!
いや…っ そういうワケじゃ｡
《そりゃ好きだけど…》
I'll admit that I'm in love with her.
ウホンッ｡室長にまでは 伝わって
ないのかもしれませんが…｡
You may not be aware of this...
彼女の志は
他のメンバーとは異なります｡
But her motivation for becoming an astronaut is somewhat unique.
I want to board the ISS to be able to develop new treatments for incurable diseases.
⦅私が ＩＳＳ搭乗を
希望するのは➡
難病に効く新薬開発に
こうけん
貢献するためです｡➡
エーエルエス
特に 私の父を苦しめたＡＬＳを➡
In particular, I wish to rid the world of ALS,
the disease that took my father.
この世から
なくしてしまいたいんです⦆
せりかさんの ＩＳＳにかける
思いの強さを知ってる者なら➡
I believe that anyone who knew how strongly she wishes to board the ISS would relinquish this spot to her.
たぶん 僕じゃなくても
譲ると思います｡
けんとう
なるほど｡検討しておこう｡
I see, I'll consider it.
君の今後についてもね｡
And I'll have to decide what to do with you.
失礼します！
Thank you!
《これで良かったんだ》
I did the right thing...
Yes! I did the right thing!
《そう！これで良かった》
Did I do the right thing?!
《良かったか!?》
《なんか最後
気まずい空気だったぞ｡➡
It got a little awkward at the end...
Was the chief angry?
室長を怒らせたんじゃ…!?》
《いやいや…決定権は
俺にあったんだ｡➡
No, it was my decision.
It was the right thing.
大丈夫に決まってる！》
《こんな時 どうすべきかは
わかってた》
I always knew what I'd do in this situation.
(シャロン)⦅迷った時はね➡
When in doubt, don't worry over what's right.
｢どっちが正しいか｣なんて
考えちゃダメよ⦆
⦅ん？⦆
⦅ほらムッタ 下げて下げて⦆
Huh?
Come on, Mutta. Lower your hands...
⦅｢どっちが楽しいか｣で
決めなさい⦆
Choose the answer that will be fun.
《どっちを選択するか迷ったら
どうやって決めるか｡➡
I was taught how to make tough decisions.
ちゃんと教わった通りだ》
(バトラー)どうぞ～｡
Come.
Hey, Nanba! Come with me!
ねえ 南波君！来て 来て！
どしたの？
(北村)せりかちゃんがやったよ｡➡
What is it?
Serika pulled it off!
She's been chosen for the backup crew on the ISS mission!
ＩＳＳのバックアップクルーに
選ばれたんだって！
Congratulations!
(ｽﾀｯﾌ)おめでとう！
(ｽﾀｯﾌ)よかったね！
That's great!
(北村)木崎さんの控え！
She's backing up Kisaki!
Really?!
本当に!!やったね！
That's great!
《よし！良かった!!》
Good! It's how it should be!
《ビンスさんから!?》
Vince?
エヌとう
《９Ｎ棟へ来い…か》
"Come to building 9N"?
ここって何だったっけ…｡
What is this place?
Mr. Nanba...
(ビンス)ミスターナンバ！
こっちです 早く｡
This way, and hurry.
Why did you turn down a chance to make it into space quickly?
(ビンス)なぜ 断ったんですか
宇宙への一番の近道を｡
申し訳ないです｡
I feel bad about it, but I'm determined to reach the moon...
いや どうしても月へ行って…｡
私でさえ…｡
I have yet...
私でさえ
まだ月へは行けてないんですよ｡
I have yet to go to the moon.
At a given time, only a set number of astronauts undergo lunar training.
月面滞在に向けた訓練にも
定員数があり➡
And the administration is very particular about who is chosen.
組織としての
きょよう
許容能力もまだ低い｡➡
希望者が すぐに訓練を受けられる
ような態勢にはなってません｡
They do not accept people because they wish to train.
イエス
君はただ｢ＹＥＳ｣と
答えるべきでした｡
You should have just accepted the spot.
バトラー室長が考えた
これからの君の研修先はここです｡
Chief Butler has found a new place for you to train.
こ…ここは!?
Wh-What is this place?
ここは バギーやローバー➡
This is where buggies, rovers, and other vehicles are developed for use on the moon's surface.
その他
ぶしょ
月面基地局の開発部署です｡
彼らは ここの技術者たち｡
They're the engineers here.
(ピーター)なんだぁ？
まぁ～た男なの？
What's this? Another man?
(ハロルド)新人のようだね｡
He looks new.
Listen carefully, Mr. Nanba...
いいですか ミスターナンバ｡➡
Beginning today, you will work with them to develop and improve the buggies.
今日から君は ここで彼らとともに
バギーの開発･改良業務に➡
加わってもらいます｡➡
バトラー室長の話では 彼らは
クルーオフィスから出された➡
Chief Butler informed me that a request from the crew office has had them stuck for eighteen months.
注文に応えられず この１年半
ずっと頭を抱えた状態です｡➡
君が加わったことで
どうなるものでもないでしょうが➡
I doubt you'll be much help,
but new astronauts are expected to build experience this way.
新人の宇宙飛行士は皆
こういう研修を積み重ねて➡
いくものです｡
期限はありません｡➡
There is no deadline.
Some astronauts do a good job and move on after a few months.
良い働きを見せ 数ヶ月で終えた
飛行士もいれば ４年５年と➡
Some remain in the same role for four or five years.
ダラダラ続けた者も
かつていました｡➡
とにかく君は 日々の基本訓練と
ここでの業務を続けながら➡
In any case, you should continue daily basic training and work here until you get new orders.
次の指示を待って下さい｡
はい…｡
《次の指示…》
Yes, sir.
New orders...
《まずいな これは…➡
This doesn't sound good...
I could be stuck here for years.
何年も待たされる
パターンな気がするぞ》
《いや 実際そうかも…》
Maybe that's their goal.
(ビンス)ミスターナンバ｡
Mr. Nanba.
ふん｡
はじめまして ど～も｡
Nice to meet everyone.
I was hoping for a girl.
僕 女の子が良かったなぁ～ ねえ｡
Yeah?
よろしく 僕はダン！➡
Nice to meet you! I'm Dan.
無人探査機ギブソンは
僕の設計だよ｡
I designed the unmanned probe Gibson.
Why don't they ever send us girls?
なんでうちには
女の子が１人も来ないんだ？
私はハロルド｡
で こっちはピーターだ｡
I'm Harold, and he's Peter.
なあ なんでうちには
女の子が来ないんだ？
Say, why don't they send us girls?
さあ…｡
Beats me.
基本的に製造は
みんなでやるんだけど➡
Typically, we all work together on a project,
ものによって
リーダーがかわる｡➡
but the leader changes, depending on what we're working on.
無人機に関する業務は
ほぼダンが指揮をとる｡➡
Dan usually takes the lead when it's an unmanned probe.
In addition to Gibson, Dan also worked on Brian.
ダンは ギブソン以外にも
ブライアンなんかも手がけた｡➡
ピーターは有人専門｡
スパイダーとかバギーとかね｡
Peter is an expert on manned vehicles, such as Spider and the buggy.
What about you, Harold?
じゃあハロルドは？ロボット系？
You specialize in robots?
私かい？
フフ…私は主に イスだ｡
Me?
I usually work on chairs.
イス!?
(ﾊﾛﾙﾄﾞ)そう イス！これを見て｡
Chairs?
That's right... Look at this.
わかるかい？
あ～あ～ イスだね｡
Can you tell what it is?
Yeah, it's a chair.
そう イス！
これはスペースシャトルに➡
Yep, it's a chair.
This used to be in a space shuttle.
ついてたイスだ｡私の父が作った｡
ヘェ～！
My father made it.
そして オリオンをはじめ
スパイダーやビートルの➡
And I've worked on most of the chairs in Orion, Spider, and Beetle.
イスというイスは
ほぼ私が手がけた｡
イスの話はもういいからさぁ➡
Enough talk about chairs.
Let's get down to business, Harold.
さっさと本題に入りましょ
ハロルド君｡
だね｡
Sounds good.
知ってるわね？
月面バギーちゃんよ｡
Recognize this?
This is a buggy.
君の弟が谷に
落っこちたのも このタイプ｡
Same model as the one that fell in the ravine with your brother.
なるほど これでしたか｡
I see... So this is the one.
あの事故のあと 落ちたバギーを➡
After the accident,
the buggy was pulled from the ravine, and they found damage all over.
谷から引き上げたら
あちこち故障が確認されたって➡
話でね｡そしたら上は
こう言ってきたの｡➡
So our bosses gave the order...
落ちても壊れないバギーに
してくれ｡あるいは➡
Design a buggy that won't take damage if it falls into a ravine.
Or else...
落ちないバギーにしてくれってね｡
Design a buggy that won't fall.
That's our current problem.
というわけなんだけど
なんかいい案ある？
Got any ideas?
えっ…ん…そ そうだなぁ｡
O-Oh...
Did you have to put me on the spot?
《急に言われても…》
やっぱり女の子がいいと思うんだ｡
どうせ誰か来るなら｡➡
They might as well have sent a girl...
女の子が来てくれたら
多分仕事もうまくいくと思うんだ｡
I have a feeling that with a girl around, we'd do a better job.
(ハロルド)月の砂･レゴリスは
非常に細かい｡➡
Regolith, lunar dust, is very fine.
The texture surface is similar to new snow.
地面は新雪の降り積もった
雪山に似てるんだ｡➡
で バギーの操縦性をよくするには
タイヤとブレーキの改良｡
So, to improve buggy control,
we have to look at the tires and brakes.
我々は まずそこを
重点的に考え直してる｡
We're currently trying to redesign those areas.
《自動車開発会社をクビになり
業界からも締め出された私が➡
I was fired from my job at an auto company and blacklisted from the industry.
But after two hectic years, I finally became an astronaut...
どとう
なんだかんだと怒涛の２年で➡
よくやく宇宙飛行士にまで
なれたというのに…》
最初の仕事が
また自動車開発とは｡
Only to go back to designing automobiles.
ふっ…皮肉なもんだぜ｡
Unbelievable.
えっ じゃあバギーを作るのに➡
Wait, you've never hired professional auto engineers to work on buggies?
今まで車の専門家を
雇わなかったってこと？
そういうことだね｡
予算的な面でも➡
That's right.
With our budget, hiring from commercial auto companies is impossible.
大手車メーカーのプロを
雇うなんてのは無理なことだ｡
And the pros see no reason to work for us at a lower rate.
そのプロから見ても
ギャラの安いうちで仕事する➡
利点はないわ｡
よって全てＮＡＳＡ独自の技術｡
So NASA develops everything in-house.
独自でこんなの作れるなんて…
すげぇな！
This was developed in-house?
That's impressive.
ハッハーン！
それがＮＡＳＡというものよ｡
That's what NASA's about!
でもまあ 今回に限っては みんな
ちょっと諦めムードなんだけど｡
But we're all about ready to give up on this current problem.
《諦め…》
Give up.
⦅とにかく君は
日々の基本訓練と➡
In any case, you should continue daily basic training and work here until you get new orders.
ここでの業務を続けながら
次の指示を待って下さい⦆
⦅はい…⦆
Yes, sir.
I was convinced that I would be left waiting out here for years,
《これは何年も待たされる
パターンに違いないと➡
諦めのような覚悟を
決めかけたあの時…》
and I was ready to give up...
⦅ミスターナンバ⦆
Mr. Nanba.
But Vince snapped me out of it.
さえぎ
《それを遮るように
ビンスさんの声》
⦅とにかく君はここで
何らかの成果をあげて下さい｡➡
You must produce results here.
それができれば君にも…⦆
If you're able to do that, you'll have a shot
⦅月ミッションのバックアップ
クルーへの道が開けます⦆
at a backup crew spot for a lunar mission.
《ふと ビンスさんの背を 目で
追った｡その視線の上方には➡
As I watched Vince walk away, my gaze drifted up.
There was a needlessly large banner that displayed NASA's passion.
ＮＡＳＡの熱意を描いたかの
たれまく
ような ムダにでかい垂幕｡➡
私はその風景に運命のお告げ的な
意味合いを勝手に感じ取り➡
I took the sight as an omen of things to come.
諦めのような覚悟を 鼻で笑った》
And I laughed off my determination to give up.
正直 タイヤもブレーキも➡
Honestly, after racking our brains on changing the tires and brakes, we've been coming up with nothing.
今以上のものを求められても
頭がねじれるばっかりだわ｡
I mean, they're essentially perfect as they are.
だって ほぼ完璧だもん｡
でも このままじゃ僕らの➡
But if we do nothing, we'll take a hit to our pride as NASA engineers.
ＮＡＳＡの技術者としての
プライドがさ…｡
《落ちないバギー…か》
A buggy that won't fall, huh?
It's been so long since I looked up at the moon
Though it's always keeping a cold eye on me
Yeah, it always keeps a cold eye on me
I wanna rough up this rotten way home
But even if it makes me mad
I can't take my eyes off it. Yeah, I can't take my eyes off it
I can't take my eyes off that dazzling smile
What did I want back then?
What was I looking for?
I should've known my tears would take me to my dreams
Blow this gloomy reality away for me
I want to see how tiny our huge worries seem
From up in that dark ocean of space
Next time, on
Space Brothers
#71 Rehearsal
As I work on the buggy, Hibito and I are featured on a magazine cover in spacesuits.
＜バギー開発の一方
私と日々人は 宇宙服姿で➡
雑誌の表紙を飾ることに｡
ムフフフ かっこ良すぎる＞
I think I look pretty cool.
＜と思いきや＞
(日々人)＜ムッちゃん｡➡
Mu, you look weird...
その格好 変だよ＞
Next time, on Space Brothers:
"Rehearsal"
Mr. Hibbit!
イェーイ！
やぁ みんな 僕 ヒビット！
Yay!
Hey, everyone! I'm Hibbit!
月へＵＦＯを探しに行く
仲間を探してるんだ！
I'm looking for friends to help me search the moon for UFOs.
Want some carrots?
ニンジン食べる？
Yay! Chief Butler!
イェーイ！バトラー室長！
ミスターヒビット…｡
Mr. Hibbit.
I found a friend!
仲間 見つけたよ！
もう月に行っていい!?
Can I go to the moon now?
ウホー ウッホッホ…｡
ダメだ｡
No.
Eh?
きょうさにゅうとつきん
え!?この胸鎖乳突筋が？
Look at this sternomastoid!
だいたいしとうきん
大腿四頭筋が？
These quadriceps!
何それ？
What are you doing?
ゴホン｡そうじゃなくて
まだ仲間が足りん｡
No, I mean you need more friends.
ニンジン食べる？
Want some carrots?
I'll pass. I only eat meat.
ワシは…いや 私は肉しか食わん｡
And to go to the moon, you also need training.
それに月に行くには
訓練も必要だ｡
Okay, got it!
ＯＫ！よ～し！
そっか！行ってくる！イェーイ！
Right, I'm off! Yay!
僕と一緒に月を目指そう！
イェーイ！
Let's head to the moon together!
Yay!
どんな訓練か
まだ言ってないけど？
I didn't tell you what kind of training.
ま～た こ～ん～ど～！
See you next week!